SCARPARO Gabriele

Software Engineer

+3 years of experience in the digital sector

Profile

Gabriele Scarparo has over 3 years of experience in Information Technology. After his web development training, he started working in the IT world, first as a Full Stack Web Developer, and then as a Technical and Functional Consultant for Microsoft Dynamics 365 CRM.

Experience at CGI

Thales T360 (09/2023 à 08/2024)

Consulting and development of a Microsoft Dynamics 365 CRM - Sales solution for Thales, a French electronics group specialized in aerospace, defense, security, and ground transportation.

- Conducting business needs analysis
- · Leading or participating in requirements gathering workshops
- Assessing the current system and identifying areas for improvement
- Proposing tailored techno-functional solutions
- Preparing comprehensive functional and technical documentation
- Developing enhancements and implementing new functionalities in C# and JavaScript
- Performing unit tests to ensure quality and reliability

Thales Platform (09/2023 to present)

Consulting and development of a Microsoft Dynamics 365 CRM - Sales solution for Thales, a French electronics group specialized in aerospace, defense, security, and ground transportation.

- Maintaining and improving tool performance.
- Managing solution delivery and error handling (Release Management).
- Customizing and configuring the CRM.
- Industrializing and automating SonarQube and GitLab for code quality analysis.
- Developing an executable to identify and delete Active Layers

GNFA (08/2024 à to present)

Consulting and development of a Microsoft Dynamics 365 CRM solution for GNFA, a training organization in the automotive and mobility services sector.

- Conducting business needs analysis
- Leading or participating in requirements gathering workshops
- Assessing the current system and identifying areas for improvement



Industry Experience

Web Development, Microsoft Dynamics 365

Skills

Front-End Development

Back-End Development

CRM Development

Website Development

Tools and Software

Microsoft Office 365, Wordpress,

Plugin Registration Tool, XRM Toolbox,

1

SonarQube

Environnements

Windows, Mac OS

Languages

French, Italian

- · Proposing tailored techno-functional solutions
- Preparing comprehensive functional and technical documentation
- Developing enhancements and implementing new functionalities in C# and JavaScript
- Performing unit tests to ensure quality and reliability

Other Experience

Agic Technology - Poste Italiane (10/2022 à 01/2023)

Consulting et développement d'une solution CRM Microsoft Dynamics 365 pour le compte du client Poste Italiane, le plus grand réseau de distribution de services postaux en Italie.

- · Conducting business needs analysis
- Leading or participating in requirements gathering workshops
- Assessing the current system and identifying areas for improvement
- Proposing tailored techno-functional solutions
- Preparing comprehensive functional and technical documentation
- Developing enhancements and implementing new functionalities in C# and JavaScript
- · Performing unit tests to ensure quality and reliability

Agic Technology - Uno Tech Gaz (05/2022 à 01/2023)

Consulting and development of a Microsoft Dynamics 365 CRM solution for Uno Tech – Unoenergy, a leader in natural gas and electricity supply.

- Conducting business needs analysis
- Leading or participating in requirements gathering workshops
- Assessing the current system and identifying areas for improvement
- Proposing tailored techno-functional solutions
- Preparing comprehensive functional and technical documentation
- Developing enhancements and implementing new functionalities in C# and JavaScript
- · Performing unit tests to ensure quality and reliability
- Developed and automated an executable for resetting custom "Quotes" entity parameters on January 1 each year.

Agic Technology - Fondazione Milano (01/2022 à 09/2022)

Consulting and development of a Microsoft Dynamics 365 CRM solution for Fondazione Milano, an organization founded and supported by the Municipality of Milan, operating in higher education.

- Conducting business needs analysis
- Leading or participating in requirements gathering workshops
- Assessing the current system and identifying areas for improvement
- Proposing tailored techno-functional solutions
- Preparing comprehensive functional and technical documentation
- Developing enhancements and implementing new functionalities in C# and JavaScript
- Performing unit tests to ensure quality and reliability

Technical Specializations

Microsoft Dynamics 365 CRM Customization
Web Development

Areas of Expertise

Full stack web development

Education and Certifications

Power Platform Fundamentals PL-900

Power Platform Functional Consultant PL-200

Power Platform Developer PL-400

Educational Background

Feb. 2021 – Aug. 2021: Master's in Full Stack Web Development, Boolean Tech Academy, Milan, Italy

2014: Master's in Humanities,

La Sapienza University, Rome, Italy

Graduated cum laude

2010: Bachelor's in Humanities,

La Sapienza University, Rome, Italy

Graduated cum laude

Skills Summary

Skill	Years of Experience	Skill Level*	
Technical Skills			
HTML	4	4	
CSS	4	4	
SCSS	4	4	
JavaScript	4	4	
jQuery	1	2	
C#	2	3	
PHP	1	2	
Application Knowledge			
Front-End Development	3	2	
Back-End Development	3	2	
API	3	3	
IT Domains			
Web Development	3	2	
DevOps	3	2	
Sector Knowledge			
Aerospace	2	3	
Professional Training	2	3	
Distribution	1	2	
Energy Supply	1	3	
Other Relevant Skills			
D365 Plugin Development (C#)	3	3	
D365 Script Development (JS)	3	3	

Skill	Years of Experience	Skill Level*
Solution Maintenance and Delivery	3	3
Wordpress	3	2
Bootstrap	3	2
SonarQube	1	2
Vue.js	2	2
React	1	2
Laravel	1	1

^{*}Niveau de compétence : 1 = Basic, 2 = Intermediate, 3 = Advanced, 4 = Expert